## **Arizona Claude Edwards**



Washington, DC 202 888 5614

arizonace@gmail.com



Skills				
Skill	YoE	Engagement	Rating	Description/Keywords
Classic C++	10+	~~~.	****	ATL, MFC, also: FCL, C++/CLI, OWL. etc.
Modern C++	3		★★★☆☆	STL, AIX, Solaris, Linux
C#/DotNet	8		****	Windows Forms, DLLs, Interop, Web ASP.NET
Python	2*		****	PEP-008, multiprocessing, .NET and C++ Interop
JavaScript	2*		****	Web, Bloomberg Terminal, Node, Typescript.
Java/Kotlin	5		****	Enterprise Java, Android, JNI, Web-Applets, Tomcat
Windows	10+		****	Since 3.0, Internals, SDK, GDI/+, COM/+
Web	5+		****	ASP.Net, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Frameworks
Unix	3		★★★☆☆	AIX, Solaris, Linux; Darwin (MacOS), Bloomberg
Cloud	5		***	AWS, DynamoDB, SQS, S3, Elasticsearch, Serverless
Databases	10+	<del>-\</del>	****	Design, DDL, Data Tier, SQL, NoSQL, Desktop
TCP/IP	3		****	SSH, SSL/TLS; WS_FTP - fastest FTP client at the time
IPTV	5		****	ASP.Net MRML to set-top-box, VHO integration.

I have a strong inventory of current and refreshable skills and solution building experience. Various jobs shifted my focus between skills and introduced new ones. The table above depicts my estimates of:

◇ accumulated experience; ◇ engagement over time; ◇ overall self rating.

I look forward to opportunities to demonstrate my skills, and contribute positively to your organization.



## **Aspects**

Multi-Sector Experience in Financial, Healthcare, Education, Defense, Internet, TV, and other industries.

Travel/Consulting Traveling for trade shows, client meetings, collaboration, and recruiting.

User Experience UX/UI designing, building, testing including for limited input devices such as phones and TVs.

Multimedia Programming, encoding, decoding, and delivering image, video, and music formats.

Algorithms Efficiently identifying and applying the appropriate algorithms and data structures.

Experience and recognition as team lead, principal developer, guide, and mentor.

Low level coding Coding at the bit level, endianness, protocols, layouts, MIL-STD-1553, Arduino, etc.

**Education** References

BSc in Computer Science with Math Minor Georgia State University linkedin.com/in/arizona-edwards#recommendations

 **Work Experience Summary** 

Amazon Software Development Engineer II Dec 2016 to Feb 2023

Developed cloud-based, large-scale financial microservices in Java, Kotlin, and AWS.

**Bloomberg** Senior Software Engineer Jun 2013 to Jun 2016

Developed enterprise data delivery solutions concerning fixed income securities in C++, Python, SQL, etc.

**Georgia Tech Research Institute** Contract Programmer Apr 2012 to May 2013

Developed software to test aircraft missile defense systems using MILSTD1553 in C++, C# and Python.

Alcatel-Lucent Solution Line Manager May 2009 to Mar 2012

Implemented software solutions for IPTV television and telephone service providers using C#, SQL, Java, etc.

AT&T Contract Programmer Jan 2007 to Dec 2008

Developed interactive IPTV software for the U-Verse platform in C#, JavaScript, and SQL.

Agile Technologies LLC Contract Programmer Jan 2006 to Mar 2006

Developed an Active-X control for Greyhound PackageXpress in C++

**NextGen Healthcare Information Systems** Consultant Jan 2005 to Aug 2006

Implemented regulatory and migration solutions for healthcare providers in C#, SQL, Excel, etc.

**taxslayer.com** Senior Developer Sep 2003 to Nov 2004

Developed online tax filing software in VB.Net, C# and SQL and using MSMQ.

**Ipswitch** Principal Software Developer Mar 1999 to Sep 2003

Developed versions of WS\_FTP and other retail Internet software in C++.

**Asymetrix** Contract Programmer Jan 1997 to Feb 1999

Implemented online eLearning solutions for enterprises in ToolBook OpenScript, C++, etc.

**Delta Airlines** Senior Contract Programmer Jan 1996 to Nov 1996

Developed airline reservations system software in C++.

**The Federal Reserve Bank** Contract Programmer May 1994 to Dec 1995

Developed internal accounting and management software in C++ and SQL.

**Nova Information Systems** Contract Programmer Sep 1993 to May 1994

Developed ETL and analysis software for credit card transaction data in VB, C, and C++.

**The Hypermedia and Visualization Lab** Multimedia Technologist Jul 1992 to Aug 1993

Developed Computer Based Training and kiosk systems, maintained multimedia technology in the lab.

**The Georgia Assessment Project** Solution Generalist Jul 1989 to Aug 1992

Produced standardized tests for the state of Georgia.